Guide to the Elinor Miller Papers 1977-2004 MSS 178 MSS 178
Fales Library and Special Collections
Elinor S. Miller Papers
1977-2004
MSS 178
Fales Library and Special Collections
1.0 linear feet (2 boxes)
The Elinor Miller Papers consist largely of letters to Miller from Michel Butor, a prominent French author, and of Miller's collection of published material by or about Butor. Some of Miller's own letters to Butor are included, and some of her correspondence on the subject of Butor. Also included are various mixed media focusing on several artists with whom Butor often collaborated, and whom Miller also studied in their relation to the author.
Provenance
The collection was donated by the family of Elinor Miller in 2004.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival materials.
Biographical Note
Elinor Miller was an English professor at Embry Riddle University and a renowned scholar of the work of Michel Butor. After their first meeting in 1977, Miller and Butor became friends and close colleagues, collaborating on translations, catalogues, and lectures. Miller's long study of Butor's work resulted in the publication of several essays and translations, and culminated with the publication of her book, Prisms and Rainbows: Michel Butor's Collaborations with Jacques Monory, Jiri Kolar, and Pierre Alechinsky, in 2002.
Michel Butor was one of the pioneers of the Nouveau roman in France. The New Novel surfaced in France in the early 1950s (though some works predate this estimate by several years), and remained the dominant form of avant-garde literature throughout the 1950s and early 1960s. Michel Butor, whose novel La Modification won the Prix Renaudot in 1957, helped this bold new écriture gain wider acclaim both in France and abroad. He later branched out to work on critical essays, poetry, non- fiction, non-non-fiction, translations, artistic and musical collaborations, and much more.
Scope and Content Note
From the moment Elinor Miller and Michel Butor met in 1977 at the University of Louisville, they had a natural interest in each other's work: Butor's artistic, literary, and critical production was prolific, and Miller was a well-known scholar of his work. As a translator, she was responsible for the dissemination of much of his writing to the English-speaking world, and her essays appeared in numerous journals. Their initially professional relationship quickly turned into a friendship that would last nearly thirty years, until her death in 2004.
The most important aspect of the collection is the correspondence of Butor to Miller spanning the duration of their friendship, as well as several manuscripts, photocopies, and carbon copies of Miller's letters to Butor. Also included are various mixed media that focus on the works of artists with whom Butor collaborated, and those whom Miller studied in relation to Butor. Finally, the collection includes an array of publications by or about Michel Butor. Miller's own essays figure prominently, but there are also numerous primary and secondary publications, collaborations, volumes of literary journals consecrated to the author, and catalogues. The collection also includes some extremely rare limited edition publications either purchased by Miller or presented to her as gifts by Butor.
SERIES I: Correspondence - Butor to Miller
This series contains the meat of the collection: the collection of Michel Butor's letters to Elinor Miller from 1977 to 2004. The letters are all collages with moving pieces, images, and text. Some include family photos, invitations to exhibition openings, conference programs, collaborative postcards, and more.
SERIES II: Correspondence - Miller to Butor
This series is far less comprehensive, as Butor donated his letters from Miller to the Bibliothèque Nationale de France, and Miller did not keep copies of all of her letters to Butor. The ones that she did keep offer an insight into the nature of her relationship with Butor, as well as into her character. It is unclear why she kept these letters in particular. This series also includes clippings and photos that Miller had intended to send along to Butor, and correspondence between Miller and various other people who have some connection to Butor.
SERIES III: Mixed Media/ Collaborations
This series is comprised of mixed media depicting the work of several artists with whom Butor collaborated. Miller wrote on these artists and their collaborations with Butor, and taught them as well. There are slides, photos, photo CDs, and audiocassettes. There is also a VHS of a Butor interview.
SERIES IV: Printed Material
This series contains both scholarly publications on Butor (subseries A) and catalogs of various museum exhibitions featuring his artwork (subseries B).
Subseries A: Secondary Publications
Subseries B: Museum Catalogs
Arrangement
Series I and II are arranged chronologically. Slides and photos in Series III have been kept in their original groupings, and Series IV is arranged alphabetically within each subseries.
Series I: Correspondence, Butor to Miller
Series II: Correspondence, Miller to Butor and Others
Series III: Mixed Media/Collaborations
Series IV: Printed Material
OVERSIZE Series IV: Printed Material
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated and moved to the Fales Library's book collection. These items have been cataloged at the item level in
Bobcat
, NYU's online catalog. Records for these items can be retrieved through a "related name" search. The separated materials are arranged in two categories: Primary Works by Michel Butor, and Collaborations between Butor and others.
Primary works by Michel Butor.
Butor, Michel. 6810000 litres d'eau par seconde. Gallimard, 1965
Butor, Michel. L'aède en exil par Hölderlin. Cognac: Fata Morgana, 2000.
Butor, Michel. Á la frontière. Paris: ELA La Différence, 1996.
Butor, Michel. Appel: suite pour un violoncello en détresse. Péronne: Dumerchez, 2000.
Butor, Michel. "Apres le Roman." New Novel Review. 3:1 1995)
Butor, Michel. Au jour le jour. Plon, 1989.
Butor, Michel. Au rendez-vous des amis. L'Amourier, 2003.
Butor, Michel. Avant-Goût. Rennes: UBACS, 1984.
Butor, Michel. Avant-Goût II. Rennes: UBACS, 1987.
Butor, Michel. Avant-Goût III: L'Appel du large. Rennes: UBACS, 1989.
Butor, Michel. Avant-Goût IV: En Mémoire. Rennes: UBACS, 1989
Butor, Michel. Baltazarade. Montréal: Éditions la Palinte, 1997.
Butor, Michel. "BILAME ou DIODE." French Literature Series. 11 (1983) 125-138.
Butor, Michel. Boomerang. Gallimard, 1978.
Butor, Michel. Brassée d'avril. Paris: É.L.A., undated.
Butor, Michel. Chantier. Gourdon: Collection Deleatur, 1985.
Butor, Michel. Curriculum Vitae: Entretiens avec André Clavel. Plon, 1996.
Butor, Michel. Dans les Flammes: Chanson du moine à Madame Nhu. Paris: E.L.A., 1988.
Butor, Michel. Degrés. Gallimard, 1960.
Butor, Michel. Description de San Marco. Gallimard, 1963.
Butor, Michel. D'un jour a l'autre. Rosporden: Éditions Hôtel Continental, 1987.
Butor, Michel. Échanges: carnets 1986. Nice: Z'Editions, 1991.
Butor, Michel. L'Embarquement de la Reine de Saba. E.L.A., 1989.
Butor, Michel. L'emploi du temps. Paris: Les Éditions de Minuit, 1957.
Butor, Michel. Entretiens: Quarante ans de vie littéraire, vol. I. Joseph K., 1999.
Butor, Michel. Entretiens: Quarante ans de vie littéraire, vol. II. Joseph K., 1999.
Butor, Michel. Entretiens: Quarante ans de vie littéraire, vol. III. Joseph K., 1999.
Butor, Michel. Envois. Gallimard, 1980.
Butor, Michel. "Escrituras, una pasión por la inventión estética." Revista Anthropos. 178-179, 1998.
Butor, Michel. Essais sur les essais. Gallimard, 1968.
Butor, Michel. Explorations. Lausanne: Editions de l'Aire, 1981.
Butor, Michel. Exprès. Gallimard, 1993.
Butor, Michel. La Forme Courte. Marseilles: Le Temps Parallele Éditions, 1991.
Butor, Michel. Frontières. France: Le Temps Parallèle Éditions, 1985.
Butor, Michel. Frontiers. Trans. Elinor and Warren Miller. Birmingham, Alabama:Summa,1989.
Butor, Michel. "Gammes Polaires." Remanences: Revue de Littérature Générale. Issue 1, 1993.
Butor, Michel. Le Génie du lieu. Paris: Bernard Grasset, 1984.
Butor, Michel. Géographie Parallèle. L'Amourier, 1998.
Butor, Michel. Gyroscope. Gallimard.
Butor, Michel. Herbier Lunaire: poèmes. Paris: E.L.A, 1984.
Butor, Michel. Histoire extraordinaire: essai sur un rêve de Baudelaire. Gallimard, 1961.
Butor, Michel. Ici et lá. Publisud, 1997
Butor, Michel. Illustrations. Gallimard, 1964.
Butor, Michel. Illustrations II. Gallimard, 1969.
Butor, Michel. Illustrations III. Gallimard, 1973.
Butor, Michel. Illustrations IV. Gallimard, 1976.
Butor, Michel. Improvisations on Butor: transformation of writing. Oppenheimer, Louis, Ed. Trans. Elinor Miller. Gainesville: Florida, 1996.
Butor, Michel. Improvisations sur Balzac I: Le Marchand et le genie. Paris: Éditions de la Difference, 1998.
Butor, Michel. Improvisations sur Balzac II: Paris à vol de l'archange. Paris: Éditions de la Difference, 1998.
Butor, Michel. Improvisations sur Balzac III: Scènes de la Vie Féminine. Paris: E.L.A., 1998.
Butor, Michel. Improvisations sur Flaubert. Paris: E.L.A., 1984.
Butor, Michel. Improvisations sur Henri Michaux. Fata Morgana, 1985.
Butor, Michel. Improvisations sur Michel Butor. Paris: E.L.A., 1993.
Butor, Michel. Improvisations sur Rimbaud. Éditions de la Différence, 1989.
Butor, Michel. Intervalle. France: Éditions Gallimard, 1973.
Butor, Michel. Le japon depuis la France: un rêve à l'ancre. Paris: Hatier, 1995.
Butor, Michel. Letters from the Antipodes. Athens and London: Ohio UP, 1993.
Butor, Michel. Mais où sont les rouilles d'antan. Fata Morgana, 1999.
Butor, Michel. Matière de Rêves. Gallimard, 1975.
Butor, Michel. Matière de Rêves IV: Quadruple fond. Gallimard, 1981.
Butor, Michel. Matière de Rêves V: Mille et un plis. Gallimard, 1985.
Butor, Michel. Michel Butor: présentation et anthologie. Paris: Seghers, 2003.
Butor, Michel. Mobile. Gallimard, 1962.
Butor, Michel. Les mots dans la peinture. Paris: L'Editions d'Art Albert Skira, 1969.
Butor, Michel. Passage de Milan. Paris: Les Éditions de Minuit, 1954.
Butor, Michel. Patience. Paris: Éditions A.M. Métailié, 1991.
Butor, Michel. Portrait de l'artiste en jeune singe. Gallimard, 1967.
Butor, Michel. Pour Tourner la page. France: Actes Sud, 1997.
Butor, Michel. Quant au livre: Triptyque en l'honneur de Gauguin. Bibliothèque Nationale de France, 2000.
Butor, Michel. Répertoire I. Paris: Les Éditions de Minuit, 1960.
Butor, Michel. Répertoire II. Paris: Les Éditions de Minuit, 1964.
Butor, Michel. Répertoire III. Paris: Les Éditions de Minuit, 1968.
Butor, Michel. Répertoire V. Paris: Les Éditions de Minuit, 1982.
Butor, Michel. Réseau aérien. Gallimard, 1962.
Butor, Michel. Le retour du boomerang. Paris: P.U.F., 1988.
Butor, Michel. Le rêve d'Irénée. Cercles, 1979.
Butor, Michel. Rêve de Conjurations. Girard, 1975.
Butor, Michel. La Rose des Vents. Gallimard, 1970.
Butor, Michel. Second sous-sol. Gallimard, 1976.
Butor, Michel. Le Sismographe Aventureux. Paris: E.L.A., 1999.
Butor, Michel. Sueurs du Temps: Poèmes. Domens, 1997.
Butor, Michel. Transit A. Gallimard, 1992.
Butor, Michel. Travaux d'approche. Gallimard, 1972.
Butor, Michel. Troisième dessous. Gallimard, 1977.
Butor, Michel. L'Utilité poétique. Saulxures: Circé, 1995.
Butor, Michel. Vanité. Balland, 1980.
Butor, Michel. Un Viseur dans ma tête. Médiathèque Intercommunale, 2002.
Butor, Michel. Zone franche. Fata Morgana, 1989.
Collaborations between Michel Butor and others.
Aver, Michèle; Butor, Michel. Butor Photographie. Paris: Photogalerie, 2002.
Badin, Georges; Butor, Michel. À Perte de vue. Carte Blanche, 2001.
Bosseur, Jean-Yves; Butor, Michel. Chants du labyrinthe. Le Coudray: Chauveau, 1999.
Butor, Marie-Jo; Butor, Michel. La Besace à poèmes. Cannes-la-Bocca: Plein chant, 2001.
Butor, Marie-Jo: Butor, Michel. Dialogue avec Arthur Rimbaud. L'amourier, 2001.
Cassel, Axel; Butor, Michel. Regards entre les branches. Spuren, 2001.
Caujolle, Christian, Ed. Photographier la guerre? Bosnie, Croatie, Kosovo. Texte de Michel Butor. 2000.
Dorny; Butor, Michel. Caractères. Imprimerie Nationale, 1993.
Druet, Roger; Butor, Michel. Le Cercle des Muses. Voix d'Encre, 1996.
Godard, Maxime; Butor, Michel. Les Fantômes de Laon. Reims: Dumerchez, 1999.
Hugo, Victor. L'Art d'être grand-père. Gallimard: 2002. [Préface par Michel Butor]
Jeannet, Fréderic-Yves; Butor, Michel. De la distance: déambulation. Rennes: Éditions Ubacs, 1990.
Koenig, J.F.; Butor, Michel. Le Corbeau revient vers la Côte Nord-Ouest. Nice, 1998.
Kolar, Jiri; Butor, Michel. Victor Hugo Écartelé: L'Esperance de l'Encre. Aencrages and Co., 1988.
Kolar, Jiri; Butor, Michel. L'Oeil de Prague. Paris: E.L.A., 1996.
Launay, Michel; Butor, Michel. Résistances. Paris: Universitaires de France, 1983.
Leick, Joel; Butor, Michel. Le fil à quoi tient notre vie. Aencrages and Co., 1996.
Leroux, Jean-Baptiste; Butor, Michel. Alpes: ou le tarot des cimes. Éditions du Chêne, 1998.
Longuet, Patrick. Quarante-trois artistes avec Michel Butor. Éditions Comp'Act, 2001.
Lounbert, Thierry; Butor, Michel. Dragons du soir. 1999. [pamphlet]
Maccheroni, Henri; Butor, Michel. Paris ville-ténèbres. Editions Léo Scheer, 2001.
Masurovsky, Gregory; Michel Butor. Comme Shirley. Paris: Imprimerie Arte, 1966.
Minkoff, Gérald; Olesen, Muriel; Butor, Michel. Dégel Parfum. 1990.
Minkoff, Gérald; Butor, Michel. Bel Vedere/Entre Vues/Zwischen Zeiten. Manpower, 1988.
Perros, Georges; Butor, Michel. Correspondance: 1955-1978. Joseph K., 1996.
Peverelli, Cesare; Butor, Michel. Le Rêve de l'Ombre. Nouveau Cercle Parisien du Livre, 1979.
Sicard, Michel; Butor, Michel. Alechinsky dans le texte. Paris: Galilée, 1994.
Sicard, Michel; Butor, Michel. Alechinsky: Frontieres et bordures. Éditions Galilée, 1984.
Sicard, Michel; Butor, Michel. Alechinsky: Travaux d'impression. Galilée, 1964.
Sicard, Michel; Butor, Michel. Collation. L'instant perpetual, 1991.
Sicard, Michel; Butor, Michel. En marge. Paris: Orte, 1992.
Sicard, Michel; Butor, Michel. Problèmes d l'Art Contemporain à partir des travaux d'Henri Maccheroni. Paris: Christian Bourgeois, 1983.
Vecchiet, Jean-Michel; Butor, Michel. Vingt blocs de charbon. Toulouse: Éditions Ombres, 1997.
Villers, André; Butor, Michel. Picasso-Labyrinthe. Tübingen: Rive-Gauche.
Villers, André; Butor, Michel. Musique de Chambre Noire. Mougins, 1980.
Butor, Michel; Miller, Elinor S.; Authors, French |y 20th century |v Correspondence.; Butor, Michel |x Correspondence.; Butor, Michel |x Criticism and interpretation.; Collages (visual works).; Color slides.; Correspondence.; Exhibition catalogs.; French fiction |y 19th century |x History and criticism.; French fiction |y 20th century |x History and criticism.; French poetry |y 20th century.; Literature, Experimental.; Literature, Modern |x History and criticism.; New novel (Literary movement) |x French fiction.; Photographic prints.; Sound recordings.; Videocassettes.
- Series I: Correspondence, Butor to Miller
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains Michel Butor's letters to Elinor Miller from 1977 to 2004. The letters are all collages with moving pieces, images, and text. Some include family photos, invitations to exhibition openings, conference programs, collaborative postcards, and more.
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, January 19, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, May 14, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 10, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, December 15, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 20, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, November 10, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, March 4, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 9, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, September 20, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, November 18, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, November 29, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 13,1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 20, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 9, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 9 1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, May 19, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, August 10, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, August 23, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, September 2, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 9, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, February 17, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 24, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, August 23, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, November 16, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, January 8, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, May 1, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, June 20, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, August 2, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, September 10, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 30, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 2, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 28, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, November 14, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, December 29, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 4, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, June 17, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 16, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 12, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, November 19, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, December 7, 1997, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, January 14, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, March 1, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 25, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, September 7 1998 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, November 6, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, December 16, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, March 6, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 25, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, May 16, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, June 28, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 23, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 26, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, September 17, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, November 13, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, December 8, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, January 17, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, February 7, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, February 16, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 2, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 14, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, May 16, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, May 20, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 30, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, August 11, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, September 1, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 2, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 30, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, January 21, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, February 17, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, April 5, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 3, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, January 13, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, February 1, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, May 16, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, July 11, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 22, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 23, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, December 23, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, March 19, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, October 3, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, January 18, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Correspondence from Michel Butor to Elinor Miller, undated fragments (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Series II: Correspondence, Miller to Butor and others
  Series II is less comprehensive than Series I, as Butor donated his letters from Miller to the Bibliothèque Nationale de France, and Miller did not keep copies of all of her letters to Butor. This series also includes clippings and photos that Miller had intended to send along to Butor, and correspondence between Miller and various other people who have some connection to Butor.
  - Correspondence from Elinor Miller to Michel Butor, 1977/1989 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence from Elinor Miller to Michel Butor, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence from Elinor Miller to Michel Butor, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Correspondence from Elinor Miller to Michel Butor, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence from Elinor Miller to Michel Butor, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Correspondence from Elinor Miller to Michel Butor, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Correspondence from Elinor Miller to Michel Butor, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Correspondence between Elinor Miller and Maxime Godard, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Correspondence between Elinor Miller and Lorraine Bénic, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Other Correspondence to and from Elinor Miller, Various (Box 2, Folder 92)